This type was introduced into England by Wynkyn de Worde, Caxton's successor,
Most of Caxton's own types are of an earlier character, though they also much resemble Flemish or Cologne letter.
the worst, which perhaps was the English, was a terrible falling-off from the work of the earlier presses;
were the leaders in this luckless change, though our own Baskerville, who was at work some years before them, went much on the same lines;
the ends of many of the letters such as the t and e are hooked up in a vulgar and meaningless way,
The essential point to be remembered is that the ornament, whatever it is, whether picture or pattern-work, should form part of the page,
The prison population fluctuated a great deal,
Full details of the arrangements are to be found in Mr. Neild's "State of Prisons in England, Scotland, and Wales," published in 1812.
and were occupied as a rule by ten to fifteen people when the prison was not crowded, but double the number was occasionally placed in them.
called the clerk of the papers, attends daily. End quote.
would have amounted to £68,728, and if defended,
These courts were extended two centuries later to several large provincial towns, and all were in full activity when Neild wrote,
A committee of the House of Commons investigated the charges against Bambridge, who was proved to have connived at the escape of some debtors,
was used for debtors arrested for the lowest sums within twelve miles of the palace of Whitehall;
They were made to wash and swab the ward, or they were shut out from the ward fireplace, and forbidden to pass a chalked line drawn on the floor,
notably as when numbers filled Newgate in anticipation of Lord Redesdale's bill for insolvent debtors,
others who arrived just after the time of distribution were often forty-eight hours without food. The latter might also be six days without meat.
or the keeper made them a special grant of 6 pence per diem out of the common stock;
or the sixpenny allowance was claimed for the creditors, which seldom happened, owing to the expense the process entailed.
and they were not in great demand, in order to convert them into mop-heads or cleaning-rags.
